If you are like most people
あなたが普通の人なら
there is a gap between the person you are and the person you wish to be.
自分の理想と現実にギャップがあるだろう
There are little things you think you should do and big things you ought to achieve.
為すべき小さなこと
達成したい大きなことがあるはずだ
From working out regularly, eating healthily, learning a language, working on your novel, reading more
定期的な運動から、健康的な食事、言語学習
小説の執筆、より多くの読書
or simply actually doing your hobby instead of browsing reddit.
あるいは趣味に取り組むこと
reddit の代わりにね
But it sometimes seems that to achieve your goals, you have to become a different person.
でも、目標達成には別人にならねばと
と思うことがある
Someone who is consistent, puts in more effort, has discipline and willpower.
一貫性があり、努力家で
自制心と意志の力を持つ誰かに
Maybe you have tried your hardest to be like that. And it worked!
「そんな人になろう」と邁進し
いい手ごたえかも
For a while.
しばらくは
Until you find yourself slipping back into your old ways.
気づけば、元の生活に戻っている
In the end, you always seem to fail.
結局、いつも失敗な気がする
And with every failed attempt, you become more and more frustrated and annoyed with yourself.
失敗を重ねるたび
自分へのイライラや悩みが強くなる
If you believe “success and hustle” internet, it is all your own fault:
もし成功者による過激な情報発信を信じているなら
if you don't succeed, you just didn’t want it enough and the failure is all you
「成功しないのは単に意欲不足で自己責任」
と思えてくる
But change is actually hard.
でも実際
変わることは困難だ
And as with most things in life, understanding why makes things easier.
そして、大抵の物事と同様
その理由を理解すれば容易になる
The Jungle
【ジャングル】
Imagine your brain as a lush and dense jungle.
あなたの脳は
鬱蒼とした密林のようなものだ
Moving through it, say to make a decision to do something, is like moving through an *actual* jungle:
何か決断をすることは
本物のジャングルを移動するようなもので
It is hard and it costs energy.
困難でエネルギーを要する
Your brain hates expending energy, so it came up with a trick:
脳はエネルギーの消費を嫌い
ごまかそうとする
All your actions and behaviors leave paths in the jungle of your brain.
あなたの行動や習慣は
脳内のジャングルに道を作っている
As you start doing something, you trample down some plants and make rough, improvised trails through the undergrowth.
何かを始めれば、植物を踏みつぶし
草むらにラフな小道を作ることになる
The more often you do the thing, the more pronounced the trail becomes.
繰り返すほど
小道は明確になっていき
Over time it turns into a path that is easier to tread,
徐々に歩きやすくなっていく
so you take it more often and it turns into a street.
自然と利用頻度が増え
いずれ立派な道となる
As you repeat doing the thing, over and over for years,
何年も繰り返し取り組むうち
the street turns into a highway.
その道は高速道路となり
Traversing it becomes effortless, familiar and comfortable.
この道を通ることは快適で
慣れ親しんだものになる
The more pronounced your brain highways, the more you get used to their comfort.
脳内の高速道路が確立するほど
快適さに慣れていき
So we continue to use them,
常用するようになる
which means we tend to do what we have always done.
我々は慣れた行動を反復しがちだ
This is why change is hard, especially as an adult when your jungle is criss-crossed by lots of established streets and highways.
だから変わることは難しい
大人は特に、多くの道や高速道路が確立している
To understand how those highways are built we need to distinguish between two things
この高速道路の形成過程を理解するには
概念の区別が必要だ
routine and habit,
「ルーチン」と「習慣」について
The Things You Do: Routines and Habits
【あなたの行動：ルーチンと習慣】
A routine is a sequence of actions that you carry out the same way every time because they’ve worked out well for you.
ルーチンとは、上手く行っており
何度も繰り返している行動パターンのことだ
For example, you get the same ingredients for your favorite dish and cook them in a certain order,
例えば、同じ食材を所定の手順で調理して
好きな料理を作る
because you like the taste of the result.
それが好きだからだ
Or before going to bed you set an alarm at 6:30 because this is when you want to get up.
また、目覚ましを6:30に設定する
その時間に起きたいからだ
Imagine routines executed by a wise planner.
ルーチンの構築は
優秀なプランナーが担当し
It is slow and analytical, responsible for strategizing and mental calculations.
戦略やメンタル面も考慮し
じっくりと分析する
The planner is aware of the future and carefully considers what kind of result you want.
プランナーは未来を見据え
あなたが望む結果を考慮して
Based on that, it chooses actions to achieve specific outcomes,
その結果を得るための行動が選ばれる
even if they are uncomfortable, like taking a shower after getting up.
「起床後にシャワーを浴びる」など
気の重いものでもだ
Routines can eventually turn into habits,
ルーチンはやがて習慣にかわり
which feel much easier because they are basically a sequence of actions carried out without thinking about them.
基本的に無意識で行うようになり
より簡単に感じられる
You have done them so often before that your brain considers them rewarding and a great response to a situation.
幾度も繰り返してきたので
脳は「状況に適した有意義な反応」と見なす
So a habit can feel like you’re on autopilot.
だから習慣は自動操縦のように感じるのだ
You don’t have to convince yourself to do something that’s a habit - you just do it.
習慣なら自分への説得は不要だ
ただ行動すればいい
The important thing about habits is that they are set in motion by triggers,
習慣で重要なのは
開始のトリガーがあることで
context cues that can be single things or entire situations,
それは一つの要素
あるいは状況全体かもしれず
that give your brain the signal to start the behavior or action.
行動や習慣を開始するシグナルを脳に送るものだ
You already have a lot of triggers in your life
あなたにも多くのトリガーがある
like when you see your phone, you almost always unlock the screen
スマホをみれば
ほぼロック解除をするだろう
Or you reach for the seat belt when you sit in a car.
車に座ればシートベルトに手が伸び
Or when you buy your coffee before work, you also get a cookie, even though you aren’t actually hungry.
仕事前のコーヒーと一緒にクッキーも買う
空腹でなくとも
Habits are executed by an impulsive toddler.
習慣を遂行するのは
あなたの中の幼児であり
it responds to your immediate desires, based on what is around you.
周りを見て
目先の欲求に反応する
Without considering any longer-term goals.
長期的な目標などない
for the toddler, to the Future doesn't exist and it hates hard work.
幼児は未来なんて考えないし
苦労も嫌いなのだ
So when it notices a trigger, it steers you to take this easy road inside your brain
だからトリガーに気づくと
脳内の容易なルートへと誘導される
that leads to a familiar rewarding result.
馴染んだ報酬につながるからだ
If you get coffee, the toddler also wants the cookie, just because that’s what you do every morning.
コーヒーと共に、幼児がクッキーを求めるのは
単に毎朝のことだからだ
This rewarding feeling is also how most of your bad habits started:
あなたの悪い習慣のほとんども
この報酬の感覚に始まる
chocolate is tasty, browsing reddit is occasionally mildly entertaining.
チョコレートは美味しいし
reddit はたまに少し楽しい
This is why you repeat these actions, even if they are bad for you.
だから自分のためにならないことを
繰り返すのだ
Rewarding feelings associated with an action demand to be repeated
報酬の感覚は
同じ行動の反復を要求し
こうして悪い習慣が生まれる
While the toddler sounds like a built-in, the sabotage mechanism.
内なる幼児は
ただのサボり魔のようだが
it is as important as the wise planner and actually they work together most of the time!
賢明なプランナーと同様に重要だし
大抵は同時に働いている
You need your wise planner for thinking big thoughts and parallel parking and doing your taxes.
大局を考え、縦列駐車や確定申告をするには
内なるプランナーが必要だ
But letting your wise planner do everything would cost too much energy.
だが全ての行動を彼に委ねるのは
エネルギーを使いすぎる
Outsourcing mundane and repetitive tasks to habits, managed by the toddler,
日常的で反復的な作業を
幼児にアウトソーシングすれば
allows your brain to easily manage your daily life,
脳は日常生活を容易に管理しつつ
while dealing with more complex mental challenges at the same time.
より複雑な精神的問題にも
同時に対処できるのだ
So if we want to change and introduce a new behavior into our lives,
だから、新たな行動を生活に取り入れ
変わりたいなら
we can actually use these energy saving mechanisms to make it easier.
この省エネの仕組みを利用すれば
容易になるのだ
We will focus on small things, not big ones.
大きなことでなく
小さなことに集中しよう
Improving your life a little is so much better than aiming high and changing nothing.
高い目標を掲げつつ変化しないより
生活を少し改善する方がずっと良い
Especially because small changes can do a lot over months and years.
少しの変化は、特に年月を経る中で
大きな効果を発揮するからだ
How To Build a Habit
【習慣の構築方法】
If you want to make change easier, the best way may not be to force it with will power
変化を容易にしたいなら
意志の力に委ねすぎず
but to convince your brain that it’s not that big of a deal.
「大した手間じゃない」
と脳を納得させるのが最善だ
By creating new routines and then turning them into habits.
新たなルーティンを作り
それを習慣に変えるのだ
You want your wise planner to construct that first trail
まず賢明なプランナーに
小道を作らせ
and then use your toddler to help initiate the action effortlessly.
内なる幼児に
行動の自然な継続を担当させるのだ
Let us say, you want to work out to be fitter, a very common goal.
健康のために運動をするとしよう
ごく一般的な目標だ
The first thing to do is to break down this pretty vague goal into clear, separate actions,
まず、この漠然とした目標を
個別の明確な動作に分割する
because the idea is to make the action itself as easy a threshold as possible:
これは実行のハードルを
可能な限り下げたいからだ
so small it is manageable and so specific that you don’t have to think about it a lot.
小さければ管理しやすく
明確なら考える必要もあまりない
For example, a tangible, controllable action might be “doing ten squats” every morning.
例えば「毎朝10回のスクワット」なんて
具体的で管理しやすいかも
So you can start by trying to create a routine
ではルーチンの形成を始めるが
but already include clear triggers that the toddler can pick up later on.
内なる幼児のために
明確なトリガーを組み込んでおく
Remember, a trigger is nothing more than a signal that you always associate with the action.
トリガーは常に行動を連想させるが
万能ではない
They can be visual pointers like seeing a particular object, like your training outfit.
「運動着のような特定のモノを見る」
など視覚的なものでもいいし
Or a certain time of day, or a designated place like a nearby park
特定の時間帯でも
近所の公園などの場所でもいい
or even better, all of these things combined.
これらを組み合わると
なお効果的だ
The important thing is that you always start doing your action in a specific context.
重要なのは、特定の状況下で
必ず行動を開始することだ
This trigger is the start button that will eventually set off the action automatically.
最終的に、このトリガーが
行動を自動で開始させるボタンとなる
So to establish a home workout habit with ten squats to begin with,
スクワット10回からの
運動習慣を作るなら
you could make sure to always do them with your exercise gear on, at the same place and time, like in your living room at 8am.
同じ場所と時間に、運動着で行うようにする
「リビングルームで午前8時から」など
Once you have your trigger and action,
トリガーと行動が決まれば
all you need to do is repeat them regularly,
あとは常にそれを反復すればいい
ideally every day.
毎日が理想だ
If you keep going, they will change from a routine to a habit,
継続すれば、ルーチンは習慣に変わる
from a trail to a highway.
小道が高速道路になるのだ
Don’t get this wrong, the squats will still take you energy to do –
もちろん、スクワット自体には
エネルギーが必要だ
but the decision to do them will feel much less like a chore and more like a regular part of your day.
だが行動への決断は容易に感じられ
日常の一部と思えるようになる
While this is simple, it is not easy.
単純だが、実行は容易ではない
Many things you want to turn into habits don’t offer as much instant gratification as wasting time on reddit.
習慣化したいことの多くは
reddit での時間つぶしほど射幸心を刺激しない
To make your new action easier to repeat and more likely to be picked up by the toddler,
繰り返しを容易にし
内なる幼児を動かすには
try to make it pleasurable.
楽しめる工夫が必要だ
Not necessarily by rewarding yourself after you done it,
行動後のご褒美は必須ではなく
but by making the action or behavior itself more enjoyable.
行動自体をより楽しめるようにしよう
Like only listening to your favorite podcast while working out,
運動中に好きなポッドキャストを聴くとか
or chipping away at your taxes while you wait for civilization to load the next round.
「Civilization」のロード時間に
節税を徐々に進めるとか
You need to figure out what works for you.
自分のやり方を見出す必要がある
In principle,　that's it.
基本的に、これだけだ
Frustratingly simple, like most things you can do to make your life better.
他の生活改善と同様
うんざりするほど単純だ
How long it takes for your toddler to take over and establish a habit varies widely.
内なる幼児がルーチンを受け継ぎ
習慣とする際の必要時間は幅広く
It depends on the behavior you are trying to get used to, what kind of person you are, your stress levels and many more things.
習慣化したい行動、あなたの人柄
ストレスレベル、他にも多くの要素に左右される
It takes anything between 15 and 250 days
新たな習慣の開始が
トリガーで自動化するまでに
until a new habit is kicked off automatically by its trigger.
15～250日ほどが必要だ
You won't know how long it will take for you.
必要期間は予知できない
Starting is the easy part
始めるのは簡単だ
especially in the first week or two.
特に最初の1～2週間は
Continuing to do it every day is the hard part.
難しいのは
それを毎日続けることだが
But it does get easier as you keep going.
継続するほど楽になっていく
There are no silver bullets for change.
変わるための特効薬は無いが
But the science of habits is a reminder that it is possible, no matter how old or young you are.
習慣の科学はリマインドしてくれる
「変われるし、年齢は関係ない」と
Even if you only end up doing a little more good stuff or a few new things, that’s still a success.
新たな取り組みや改善が小さなものだったとしても
それは成功なのだ
Being a little bit more healthy or knowledgable
少し健康に、物知りになることは
is a million times better than being unhappy about a thing and changing nothing.
不満を持ちながら変われないことの
100万倍いいことだ
In the end, change is a direction, not a destination.
結局のところ
変化とは目的地ではなく、方向のことなのだ
So now that we hopefully gave you a bit of insight and motivation,
ささやかな洞察や動機をご提供したところで
here is a thing we made, to make this progress easier, with design and science
変化への行動を容易にするものを
デザインと科学に基づいて作りました
Please bear in mind. You don't need to buy anything to work on yourself this is optional.
もちろん、自分の力だけで変われるのですが
オプションとして
Having said that, we struggle with change as much as anyone else,
私たち自身、変化に悪戦苦闘だったので
so we created our own habit journal, as much for ourselves as for you.
皆さんだけでなく、自分たちのためにも
習慣日記を作りました
Before we printed anything, we tested it on ourselves and got feedback from the Kurzgesagt team and exparts.
出版前に自分たちで試行し
スタッフと専門家からフィードバックをもらいました
The idea is for you to track your habit progress for your desired behavior.
理想の行動が習慣になるまでの軌跡を
自分で辿れるようにします
There is a tutorial part which guides you through the hardest part of the process step by step.
最も難しい部分を一歩ずつ案内してくれる
チュートリアルがあり
You’ll get helpful pointers, reflect on your progress and how you could make things easier for yourself.
有用な注意書きがあり、自身の歩みから
容易に取り組む方法を振り返ります
Once you get through the tutorial part the habit journaling starts,
チュートリアルの後は
習慣日記の開始です
regularly interwoven by examples, science Breaks and reflections that will hopefully keep the journey interesting.
継続を楽しめるように
具体例、科学記事や振り返りを織り交ぜています
Like our Gratitude Journal it is cloth-bound, with an embossed hardcover and printed on high-quality paper.
感謝日記と同様、エンボス加工された布製のハードカバーで
高品質紙に印刷されています
Nice to the touch and with lots of beautiful illustrations this book is compangion on your personal change journey,
手触りがよく、美しいイラスト満載のこの本は
変化への旅路のお供になります
however small or big it may be.
変化の大小を問わずです
Getting things from our shop is the best way to support Kurzgesagt and what we try to do here on the channel. Thank you for watching.
ショップでのご購入はKurzgesagtと
その活動を応援する最良の方法です
Thank you for watching.
ご視聴ありがとうございました